RG 074:008, Harry I. Thompson West Haven Genealogical Papers
Connecticut State Library
Harry I. Thompson West Haven genealogical papers
circa 1880-1900
Connecticut State Library
Thompson, H. I.
1.75 cubic feet
Notebooks and manuscript notes related to West Haven, Connecticut genealogy.
RG074_008
1939-003
Scope and Content
Notebooks and manuscript notes related to West Haven, Connecticut genealogy.
Related Material
Letters and list of portraits by Harry Ives Thompson [CSL call number StLib Archives 920 T373].
Index Terms
Persons:
Thompson, H. I.; Thompson, Clarence E
Places:
West Haven (Conn.) -- Genealogy
Document Types:
Notebooks; Research notes
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
The 42 notebooks are available on microfilm [CSL call number L.H. 4432-4434/5 (3 reels).]
Provenance
These papers were received on January 4, 1939 from Mr. Frederick W. Slater of New Haven, agent for Clarence E. Thompson, Jr. Clarence E. Thompson, Jr. inherited the papers from Harry I. Thompson.
The notebooks and manuscript notes were at one time separated. The manuscript notes were formerly catalogued as 974.62 W524t.
Container List
- Notebooks, circa 1880-1900
  Pages are numbered consecutively for Volumes 1-19. Pages are unnumbered starting with Volume 20.
  See Alternate Form Available.
  - Painter and allied families (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Beecher, Smith, Candee, Thompson families, and others (Box 1, Volume 2)
    Contains copies of deeds, wills, etc.
  - Extracts of the Colony Records, 1639-1649 (Box 1, Volume 3)
  - Records "From Town Clerks Office, New Haven, Painter, etc." (Box 1, Volume 4)
  - Records "From Town Clerks Office, New Haven, Painter, etc."; Index and Notes (Box 1, Volume 5)
  - Index to Painter family. Vital records of various families (Bristoll, Candee, Painter, Downs, Lampson, Kimberly, Stevens, Clinton, Trowbridge, Brown, Prindle, Smith, Hall, Clark, Thomas, Tolles, etc.) (Box 1, Volume 6)
  - "George Lamberton's Quarter; Division of Land; About Early Settlers West Haven, Kimberly, Benham, Stevens, etc.; Names from Congregational Society Records, 1724-1849; Names from Simeon Smith's Account book, 1820-1829; 'West-side' 'West Side Farmers' 'West Parish of New Haven' etc.; 'West Haven Green' 'Old Parsonage' Extract N.Y. Independent, etc." (Box 1, Volume 7)
  - "Division of Lamberton's Farm among Children; Index and Notes (Box 1, Volume 8)
  - "The Old Burial Ground. Hearse House. Green Fence" (Box 1, Volume 9)
  - "Seating of the 1st Meting house, with other notes, Bell, etc. Extracts from 'Barbers Antiquities'. Old School House. 2nd Church Edifice" (Box 1, Volume 10)
  - "Reynolds Genealogy, Thomas Painters Children, Roger Alling, Edward Meloy" (Box 1, Volume 11)
    Pages 881-902 are missing.
  - "Map of West Haven, 1800; Dea. Enos Smith; The older Houses in West Haven; Concerning the Simeon Smith, D.S. Thompson House; The Capt. Ichabod Smith Homestead; Gilead Kimberly House, The Reynolds Inn" (Box 1, Volume 12)
  - "Rum in West Haven, 1820-1830; Kimberly Genealogy; John M. Hubbards History of Western District; Malbon's Cove to Oyster River" (Box 1, Volume 13)
  - "Richards Genealogy and Ichabod Smith's Family" (Box 1, Volume 14)
  - Extracts from town records and notes (Box 1, Volume 15)
  - "New Haven Colonial Records, 1638-1665" (Box 1, Volume 16)
  - "New Haven Colonial Records, 1638-1665" (Box 1, Volume 17)
    See Index in volume 16.
  - Beecher family records and extracts from the town records (Box 1, Volume 18)
  - Copies of wills and notes on various families (Box 1, Volume 19)
  - "Capt. Philemon Smith's Record of Deaths. Records of West Haven Tract Society" (Box 1, Volume 20)
  - "Genealogical Notes from Mrs. Tallmadge's Mss. 'Aunt Sena's list of deaths, etc." (Box 1, Volume 21)
  - "Extracts from Auto-Biography of Thomas Painter Soldier of the American Revolution 1776" (Box 1, Volume 22)
  - "Mrs. Wm. H. Tallmadge's Book of Genealogy of the Stevens and other families; Candee Genealogy, Extracts from work of C.C. Baldwin" (Box 1, Volume 23)
  - "Index and Notes" (Box 1, Volume 24)
  - "Index and Notes" (Box 1, Volume 25)
  - "Index" (Box 1, Volume 26)
  - "Mallory" (Box 1, Volume 27)
  - "Records of Births, Marriages & Deaths, 1649-1745; Downs, Bristol, Smith; Notes of Mrs. E.P. Smith, of Milford, Conn.; Genealogy of Chas. S. Smith of Terryville, Conn." (Box 1, Volume 28)
  - "English Genealogy-Thompson" (Box 1, Volume 29)
  - "American Genealogy-Thompson" (Box 1, Volume 30)
  - "The West Haven Kimberly Families" (Box 1, Volume 31)
  - "Lamberton" and "Lieut. Saml Smith, son of George Smith, the Settler" (Box 1, Volume 32)
  - "Wm. Wilkes, Philip Leek, Humphreville, Clinton, etc." (Box 1, Volume 33)
  - "2nd Division land of Richard Hull and John Budd" (Box 1, Volume 34)
    Also contains notes on Bristol, Pardee, Painter familes.
  - Reynolds family (Box 1, Volume 35)
  - "Lieut. Robert Seeley's 2nd Division" (Box 1, Volume 36)
    Also contains notes on Mallery, Trowbridge, Stevens, Smith, Thompson, Painter, Prindle families, etc.
  - "Clarke-Clark" (Box 1, Volume 37)
  - A copy of the records of Christ Church, West Haven (Box 1, Volume 38)
  - Society Records No. 2 (Box 1, Volume 39)
  - A copy of the records of the West Haven First Ecclesiastical (Congregational) Society (Box 2, Volume 40)
  - Old houses of West Haven and division of lands (Box 2, Volume 41)
  - Index and Notes (Box 2, Volume 42)
- Unprocessed material, circa 1880-1900
  This material was received in 14 envelopes. The contents of each envelope were placed in a folder.
  - Papers (Box 3-4)